tripcentral.ca 2013-05-26

# All Inclusive Vacations | Last Minute Vacations | Vacation Packages | Cheap Flights - tripcentral.ca

The Canadian Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA) was enacted on January 1, 2001 to ensure all Canadian's basic right to privacy. PIPEDA applies to every business in Canada and covers the collection, use, storage and disclosure of personal information about identifiable individuals.

At Tripcentral.ca, we value your trust and believe in the importance of protecting the privacy of the individual. A travel enquiry and purchase requires the voluntary disclosure of personal information and an exchange of that information with various third party suppliers. We have appointed a Privacy Officer to handle requests for information; ensure our Privacy Protection Policy complies with the legislation; oversee the integrity of our systems and monitor end supplier adherence to PIPEDA.

At Tripcentral.ca, we value your trust and believe in the importance of protecting the privacy of the individual. A travel enquiry and purchase requires the voluntary disclosure of personal information and an exchange of that information with various third party suppliers. We have appointed a Privacy Officer to handle requests for information; ensure our Privacy Protection Policy complies with the legislation; oversee the integrity of our systems and monitor end supplier adherence to PIPEDA. 

The following Privacy Protection Policy was updated and posted on Tripcentral.ca on January 11, 2004. Questions regarding the policy and it's implementation should be e-mailed to privacy@tripcentral.ca or mailed to: 

**Tripcentral.ca** 2 King Street West  
Hamilton, ON L8P 1A1 **Attn: Privacy Officer**

## Privacy Protection Policy

Tripcentral.ca uses your personal information for the purposes of responding to and processing your requests for travel products and services. Personal information is also required to process refunds. Our privacy policies cover information regarding all customers and potential customers: customers we deal with face-to-face, on the telephone and online. 

## Collection of Personal Information

Tripcentral.ca collects personal information that is specifically and voluntarily provided by visiting and calling our physical locations or by visiting our website. In order to plan and purchase a travel product or service some basic personal information is required. This may include: 

  * Name, Title, Gender
  * Address
  * Phone number
  * Email address
  * Emergency contact information 
  * Credit card number and expiration date
  * Citizenship, Immigration status, Passport details
  * Birth date
  * Frequent flyer information, meal & seats preferences

## Individual Profiles

Tripcentral.ca collects your name and contact information (telephone number and email address) when a travel enquiry is opened. In order to process the request and complete a reservation additional information is collected about each traveller along with his or her preferences.

Full legal name, gender and title are required by the airlines in order to comply with Federal travel regulations.

An address is required to bind the contract and send proof of purchase. Phone and email contacts are required for communication during the purchase process and following the sale in cases of schedule changes, disrupted travel, emergency, and follow-up after travel is completed.

Credit card details are required internally or by end suppliers for settlement of purchases. Citizenship and Immigration status is required by the Travel Industry Act (TICO) to ensure travellers are advised of correct travel documentation. Place of birth, nationality, age, passport details are also required by airlines to comply with Canadian Transportation Act (CTA) regulations and governments for visas and travel documents.

Birth dates are required in order to purchase insurance, to receive special rates (e.g. senior, youth, child fares) and facilitate unaccompanied minor (UM) service.

Additional personal ID numbers and preferences such as frequent flyer numbers, past passenger numbers, car ID numbers, hotel ID numbers and seat requests are needed to accrue personal rewards and to access special rates and services. Special meal and religious requirements are collected to ensure travellers receive suitable meal service.

**Contests** Tripcentral.ca periodically provides opportunities to participate in contests. Information collected from participants is required to determine a winner and all personal information about identifiable individuals is discarded after the prize has been awarded.

**Cookies** Upon visiting the Tripcentral.ca website, your computer is automatically assigned a "cookie" (a small unique text identifier). Cookies are placed on your computer hard drive to support your visit and do not include any personal information. Cookies are stored on the local hard drive and remain there until manually deleted.

**IP Addresses** Tripcentral.ca collects Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for the purposes of administration, to gather broad demographic information and to audit the misuse of our web site.

**Computer Information** Tripcentral.ca collects certain technical information from your computer such as the operating system, web browser type and version, screen resolution, IP address and referrer site.

**Permission** By making a travel enquiry you give Tripcentral.ca permission to collect voluntarily provided personal information, and by using the Tripcentral.ca website you agree to allow a cookie to be set on your computer and the collection of personal and computer information.

Tripcentral.ca collects your name and contact information (telephone number and email address) when a travel enquiry is opened. In order to process the request and complete a reservation additional information is collected about each traveller along with his or her preferences.

## Use of Personal Information

Tripcentral.ca uses the personal information in order to process and compete travel inquires and reservations. The records are maintained for seven (7) years from date of booking (six years full calendar years plus the year of the transaction) as required by Canada Customs and Revenue Agency (CCRA). Tripcentral.ca does not sell or distribute any personal information to third parties for marketing purposes.

**Third Party Suppliers** In order to complete travel bookings certain personal information is passed on to third party Canadian and non-Canadian suppliers such as airlines, cruise lines and hotels. The information varies according to the type of travel booked. For example, a name and car ID number is required in order to complete a car reservation. A name, date of birth and place of residence is required for an insurance policy. A name, phone number, credit card number, expiry date and room preference is required to complete a sun vacation booking.

It is important to note that because Tripcentral.ca acts as the agent during the process of requesting and booking travel you are also a client and the third party supplier. As such your personal information is therefore covered by that third party suppler's privacy policy over which Tripcentral.ca has no control.

Tripcentral.ca sends the minimum required personal information to the third party suppliers and does not sell any data (individually or in bulk).

**Legal Obligations** Tripcentral.ca may be required by law to disclose certain personal information in cases of illegal activities or in order to resolve disputes that arise in the normal course of business.

**Communications** You will be contacted by telephone and email by a tripcentral.ca agent with respect to your travel enquiry. Should you not wish to engage in communications with respect to this enquiry, simply tell our agent by phone or email and they will close your travel enquiry. All marketing communications engaged by tripcentral.ca are respectful and designed to be mutually beneficial. Customers will be placed on an email newsletter list for which will contain and opt out link. The email distribution is provided by a third party company under contract for privacy/non solicitation of your email address. From time to time, a tripcentral.ca agent may follow up on our past customers by telephone or email at a time of year germane to your previous travel purchase. For example, if you traveled in the past at New Years, our agent may contact you when new pricing is loaded for the next New Year's travel period. You also have the option to never have us contact you for marketing purposes – each agent has a "do not call", "do not email", and "do not mail" (other than invoices related to travel services purchased) flag which can be set in your profile. It's important to remember that the do not contact settings are per person, and not per household.

**Spyware** Tripcentral.ca does not condone the use of spyware (i.e. pop-up window advertising) and does not employ any similar technologies. Tripcentral.ca does not sell space on the website to third parties or allow third parties access to user information.

**IP Addresses** Tripcentral.ca uses aggrigate IP address information and does not ordinarily link IP addresses to personally identifiable information. However when necessary to enforce compliance with the Terms of Sale and Terms of Use, to protect our web site or other users and to prosecute misuse, we will link individual IP addresses.

**Cookies** Portfolio management, management of individual enquiries within the portfolio and individual session management all require cookies. They are used to track advertising referrer sources and to test the effectiveness of online marketing campaigns. Aggregate statistics are used in the web site planning and development cycle and to monitor overall traffic. Cookies identify excessive users who can be tracked using IP addresses.

**Computer Information** Tripcentral.ca uses operating system, browser and screen resolution information in aggregate during the development cycle.

**Storage of Personal Information** By providing you with this Privacy Statement, Tripcentral.ca pledges continued commitment to protecting personal information. Tripcentral.ca provides appropiate physical, organizational and secure technical measures to safeguard personal information and to protect it from unauthorized access. This includes limiting access of personal information to those employees who have a business reason to use it.

**Physical Storage** All paper files are stored securely at Tripcentral.ca premises and shredded when discarded.

**Electronic Storage** To protect the confidentiality of all personal information Tripcentral.ca uses data encryption, or scrambling technologies and industry-standard firewalls. When you send personal information it is stored by Tripcentral.ca and protected by 128-bit Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology, an industry standard security protocol.

## Disclosure of Personal Information

Tripcentral.ca and its employees will maintain and protect all personal information under their control. Personal information may be reviewed electronically or in person by the identifiable individual at any time. It may also be amended or deleted at any time.

Top of page
